Today we are talking about ICICI
Prudential Life Insurance,
how to apply for the claim process,
how to make a claim, so today we will discuss this topic
and will explain how
you can apply for it online as well as
offline,
so let's start the video, the
first option to do this claim process is
that you can download the mobile application of ICICI Prudential
from Play Store
and apply it from there,
so you will get this potential
mobile application on both Android and Apple
Store, here you will see
these options, the second option visible in it is the
flame option, by
clicking on the prem card located here,
you just have to follow the instructions given in it
and keep fitting whatever details will be asked from you,
you can also download the frame form from here, first of all
you have to start the claim process by checking the policy number and date of
birth details,
after that other
necessary documents  Of these,
it has to be submitted through the application,
like more information about the policy bond
or about the nominee,
details will be asked for by the experts,
you have to fill it, about the bank details,
you have to upload that too, so
here upload the required documents like
prem settlement form, death certificate,
policy certificate and other necessary
documents, so in this way all the
documents have to be uploaded, the details have to be
folded and you can do this whole thing through that application,
after completing this you will also get information about it on SMS and mail,
and here the terms and
conditions that you are seeing in the application, you have to
read it carefully, take a
screenshot also and
submit it only after reading it carefully,
before submitting, you have to match all the details once properly
and
you will also see this toll free number, you can also inform them on that toll free number, it is
necessary to inform them through toll free medium,
so further we will talk about the
process of this application  Apart from this,
what other processes are there through which we
can make a nominee claim?
So you have to submit it in this way,
after fitting all the details,
before submitting, as I told you, you have to
recheck that the documents that have been asked for have been uploaded correctly, that you have fitted the details that have been asked for, it is very important to recheck it,
ICICI Prudential
settles the claim in one day because in the
absence of an earning member in the family, the
sooner the claim is settled with
less or no
hassles, the better it is for that family,
further we will also see that
apart from the mobile application, what other option can be used from
where the claim can be made or the
volume can be registered, so
next we will talk about this,
in ICICI Prudential, you will
also get the option of Chetnas, in which if there is
any confusion at the time of claim, then you can chat with them
and can clear that confusion, the
third option you will get is toll
free, in which you can also get some information by calling  If you have any
inquiry, you
can clear it and also
know about other processes. The fourth option is
email, through which you
can communicate with them through the same medium. If you need some additional information, you
can also get it. The fifth option is
WhatsApp. The WhatsApp number is
also visible. This is the
WhatsApp number of SSC Potential. Please save this number.
If you want to chat in any way,
get some information, get a policy
certificate or any other service,
we will also talk about it later. The
sixth option is SMS. All these options are
very good so that you can
connect with ICICI Prudential. If you can get
help in processing the application,
this is the
WhatsApp number of ICICI Prudential. If you save that number, then
this icon will
appear here.
If you write 'Hi' on WhatsApp to the ICICI Prudential number, then this is how
you will get a message:
Message from ICICI Prudential
Life Insurance. Please select.  And option
to help me sir view better here some
offices are visible till number 108 highway existing
policy I have applied for the new policy like this
so if we talk about claim then
number 8 is visible want to register for
public track claim so please like the
word 'mukti' so from here if you type keywords then
you will get its information
so if we send number 8 here
or vote then some options are visible here
please choose the option you are looking for on
one number register flame share document
right claim status document check list
so if we want to register plainly then if we
type one and send it then after this
we will see the options please latest no which
claim you want to register life insurance
claim health insurance claim if we
apply here again if we are
talking about life insurance claim
then in this way you
can also get all the information by chatting on WhatsApp and
can know the process how to click yes
sorry for medium hair loss we
committed to  Provided it is completely supported
in this favor of need you need to register
claim form online just visit here
you are getting a website link of
ICICI Prudential you have to visit it
please keep the policy number oblique
PAN and date of birth of the life assured handy
and in this way you will get all the
information through WhatsApp also
so investor this way
ICICI says use Tower four times seven
digital services for quick and
secure transactions like and ping
renewal premium paying tax and link
premium paid certificate checking fund
value buying life insurance policy and
claim also two so inverter
if you liked this video then you must give us
your suggestion on this and in future I am going to make another video
which will be based on IRDA which is the insurance
regulator the insurance claims
how IRDA helps in the insurance sector or
if there is any problem in making a claim then
how help can be taken from IRDA so
definitely watch that video for this
you must tell us  Please subscribe and
like and share our video.
See you in the next video.